m 20 0 l 209 0 b 218 0 229 11 229 20 l 229 209 b 229 218 218 228 209 228 l 20 228 b 11 228 0 218 0 209 l 0 20 b 0 11 11 0 20 0
m 115 64 l 115 35 l 171 0 l 177 0 l 133 46 l 143 52 l 179 0 l 184 0 l 159 63 l 229 107 l 229 182 l 145 96 l 135 122 l 207 227 l 137 227 l 115 172 l 115 93 l 126 76 l 115 64 l 104 76 l 115 93 l 115 172 l 93 227 l 23 227 l 95 122 l 84 96 l 0 182 l 0 107 l 70 63 l 45 0 l 50 0 l 87 52 l 97 46 l 52 0 l 59 0 l 115 35
m 71 60 b 71 0 161 0 161 60 b 161 120 71 120 71 60
m 325 0 l 355 0 l 332 47 l 354 47 l 399 136 l 369 136 l 328 53 l 288 136 l 257 136 l 325 0 m 467 0 l 497 0 l 474 47 l 496 47 l 541 136 l 511 136 l 470 53 l 430 136 l 399 136 l 467 0 m 545 1 l 583 1 l 583 14 l 568 14 l 568 19 l 583 19 l 583 30 l 568 30 l 568 34 l 599 34 l 599 30 l 583 30 l 583 19 l 599 19 l 599 14 l 583 14 l 583 1 l 611 1 b 616 1 622 6 622 10 l 622 36 l 652 0 l 678 0 l 644 41 l 622 41 l 622 47 l 596 47 l 597 54 l 625 54 l 625 68 l 541 68 l 541 54 l 572 54 l 571 47 l 545 47 l 545 1 m 583 72 l 583 85 l 569 85 l 569 90 l 598 90 l 598 85 l 583 85 l 583 72 l 611 72 b 615 72 621 78 621 82 l 653 44 l 678 44 l 644 86 l 621 86 l 621 103 l 597 103 l 597 136 l 570 136 l 564 126 l 562 136 l 542 136 l 548 107 l 568 107 l 565 121 l 571 121 l 571 103 l 547 103 l 547 72 l 583 72 m 600 107 l 620 107 l 624 124 l 653 89 l 679 89 l 642 136 l 615 136 l 618 132 l 606 132 l 600 107 m 689 0 l 716 0 l 721 15 l 732 15 l 732 30 l 718 56 l 731 56 l 735 100 l 721 100 l 717 59 l 714 64 l 714 136 l 693 136 l 693 79 l 676 79 l 707 30 l 679 30 l 679 15 l 694 15 l 689 0 m 738 0 l 804 0 b 807 0 813 6 813 9 l 813 87 l 794 87 l 794 14 l 756 14 l 756 87 l 763 77 l 763 21 l 787 21 l 787 91 l 798 91 l 798 120 l 820 120 l 812 136 l 778 136 l 778 90 l 748 136 l 723 136 l 756 87 l 738 87 l 738 0 m 257 151 l 275 151 l 297 182 l 319 151 l 337 151 l 304 197 l 304 227 l 290 227 l 290 197 l 257 151 m 337 151 l 355 151 l 377 182 l 399 151 l 417 151 l 384 197 l 384 227 l 370 227 l 370 197 l 337 151 m 425 192 l 447 192 b 445 181 427 181 425 192 l 410 192 b 414 162 458 162 462 192 l 462 206 l 425 206 b 425 210 429 212 433 213 l 462 213 l 462 227 l 433 227 b 412 227 408 203 410 192 m 462 151 l 532 151 l 532 165 l 504 165 l 504 227 l 489 227 l 489 165 l 462 165 l 462 151 m 580 172 l 580 186 l 549 186 b 543 186 543 192 549 192 l 565 192 b 589 192 589 227 565 227 l 532 227 l 532 213 l 565 213 b 570 213 570 206 565 206 l 549 206 b 524 206 524 172 549 172 l 580 172 m 592 213 l 606 213 l 606 227 l 592 227 l 592 213 m 639 172 l 665 172 l 665 186 l 639 186 b 623 186 623 213 639 213 l 665 213 l 665 227 l 639 227 b 603 227 603 172 639 172 m 700 184 b 722 184 722 215 700 215 l 700 229 b 740 229 740 170 700 170 b 660 170 660 229 700 229 l 700 215 b 680 215 680 184 700 184 m 737 172 l 782 172 b 803 172 813 177 813 198 l 813 228 l 799 228 l 799 198 b 799 186 793 187 782 187 l 782 228 l 768 228 l 768 187 l 752 187 l 752 228 l 737 228 l 737 172
本字幕由人人影视字幕组翻译
禁止用作任何商业盈利行为
翻译：冰蓝 小雷_Amber 二川 珞珞 卜小早 小泓泓 拉图
时间轴：MH 搁浅 雪贵人   后期：MythCreator
校对：圈圈 青椒  总监:  苹果果
我的名字叫奥利弗·奎恩
My name is Oliver Queen.
五年里  我被困在地狱一般的小岛上
After five years on a hellish island,
我回来只有一个目标
I have come home with only one goal--
拯救我的城市
to save my city.
但要达到目标  我不能像过去一样成为凶手
But to do so, I can't be the killer I once was.
为了纪念我的朋友  我只能伪装成另一个人
To honor my friend's memory, I must be someone else.
深切怀念托马斯·梅林
孝子
成为另一个存在
I must be something else.
《绿箭》前情回顾
Previously on "Arrow"...
我是巴里·阿伦  来自中心城市警局
I'm Barry Allen, from the Central City Police Department.
是犯罪现场调查组的工作人员
I'm with the Crime Scene Investigation Unit.
我有朋友能够帮我
I have friends that can help.
-这奇迹可能会杀死你  -动手吧
- This miracle could kill you. - Do it.
一种用来制造人体武器的血清
It was a serum designed to create human weapons.
你觉得有人找到了配方
You think someone found the recipe?
离心机和血库被盗
A centrifuge and a large supply of blood.
我觉得有人想要生产更多的血清
I think someone wants to make more of it.
-奥利弗  -他还活着吗
- Oliver! - Is he alive?
-费利西蒂  我们救不了他  -对  我们救不了
- Felicity, we can't save him! - I know. We can't.
求你救救我朋友
Please save my friend.
按住他
Hold him!
他没法活下来了
He's not going to make it.
他会活下来的  只要找到他体内有什么
He will. We just have to find out what's in his system.
一般我只处理死人
I--I--I usually only work on dead people.
-巴里  -好  他的身体做出这样的反应
- Barry! - All right, I can think of four possible diagnosis
我能想到四种可能的诊断
for what's causing his body to react this way.
现在只有三种可能的诊断了
Make that three possible diagnosis.
两种
Two.
开始胸部按压
Start chest compressions.
我要抽血检查
I need to get to his arm.
好了
Got it.
-他的静脉正在内凝结  -什么
- He's suffering from intravenous coagulation. - What?
血液里有异常肿块  就像枫糖浆一样
His blood is unnaturally clotting. It's like maple syrup.
你能救他  对吧
You can save him, right?
对
Right.
杀鼠灵
幸亏你们这里老鼠成灾
Lucky you guys have a rat problem.
你开玩笑嘛  那东西有毒
Are you kidding? That'll kill him!
如果我不这样做  他就会死
He dies if I don't.
-费利西蒂  -动手吧
- Felicity... - Do it!
一定量的老鼠药会稀释他的血液
Just the right amount of this stuff will thin his blood enough
让其重新循环
to get it circulating again.
放弃吧  奥利弗
Let go, Oliver.
他在衰弱
He's crashing.
别再挣扎了
Don't fight anymore.
奥利弗  保持清醒
Oliver, stay with me!
跟我走吧
Stay with me.
绿箭
第二季第九集
-奥利弗  放开他  -奥利弗
- Oliver, let him go. - Oliver!
出什么事了
What the hell is going on?
你被注射了一种强效凝血剂
You were injected with a strong-acting blood coagulant.
你本来快死了
You would have stroked out,
但幸运的是  你们这里有十分有效的血液稀释剂
but fortunately you had a very effective blood thinner handy.
华法令阻凝剂
Warfarin.
又叫杀鼠灵
Better known as rat poison.
他救了你的命  奥利弗
Kid saved your life, Oliver.
按照救生事件的情节发展
This is the point in a lifesaving emergency
你现在应该感谢救命恩人
where you thank the person that did the lifesaving.
-你把我的身份告诉了他  -对
- You told him who I am. - Yeah, I did.
这秘密轮不到你来泄露  费利西蒂
That's not your secret to tell, Felicity.
由我来决定谁能知晓我的身份
I decide who finds out my identity.
我们没时间等你投票
Well, we didn't have time to get your vote,
你当时昏迷不醒  即将死去
what with you unconscious and dying.
如果他离开这里  然后直接去找警察怎么办
What happens if he leaves here and goes right to the police?
-他不会那样做的  -我不会那样做的
- He wouldn't do that. - I wouldn't do that.
-我信任他  -我不信
- I trust him. - I don't!
你打算怎么办  朝他射箭吗
What are you going to do, put an arrow in him?
-我在考虑  -别担心  他开玩笑的
- I am considering it. - Don't worry, he's kidding!
你妈妈开枪打了你  你不是也来找我帮忙了吗
How is this any different from when your mother shot you and you came to me for help?
你妈妈居然开枪打你
Your mother shot you?
狄格中了箭毒  你不是也把他带来了这里吗
Or when you brought Dig down here when he was poisoned with curare.
区别在于我调查过你们两个
The difference is that I did my homework on both of you!
我从来不会随便告诉别人
I don't just tell people easily.
我不会告诉别人的
I'm not going to tell anyone.
你没必要感谢我
And you don't have to thank me,
但你该感谢她  别这么混蛋好吗
but you should thank her instead of being kind of a jerk.
奎恩先生
Mr. Queen.
来自妈妈
你能回家吗
我得回家了
I have to go home.
我在避难室里与之搏斗的男人
That man that I fought in the bunker,
他有能力批量生产岛上的血清
he has what he needs to mass produce the serum from the island.
我们得阻止他
And we have to stop him.
他抓住你脖子时  碰了你的皮肤
He touched your skin when he grabbed your neck.
我吸取了他皮肤中的残油
I was able to absorb the residual oils from his skin,
将其放入凝胶聚合物中
which, when added to a gel-based polymer,
也许能够重建他的指纹
might be able to recreate his fingerprint.
与偶像见面后总是会幻灭  对吧
Never meet your heroes, right?
妈妈
Mom?
谢谢你回家来  亲爱的
Thank you for coming home, sweetheart.
发生什么事了吗
Is everything all right?
我不知道  你妹妹把自己锁在房里
Well, I don't know. Your sister has locked herself in her room
不肯和我说话
and she won't talk to me.
-别担心  我和她谈谈  -好
- Don't worry, I'll talk to her. - Ok.
今天是圣诞节啊
It's Christmas.
是的
Yes.
但考虑到我们最近举办的盛会
But given the last gala that we threw,
今年还是不要举办圣诞派对了
I think we're going to skip this year's Christmas party.
西娅  我是奥利  开门
Thea, it's Ollie. Open the door.
现在不行  奥利
Not--not now, Ollie.
闪电妞  快开门
Speedy, open the door!
妈妈和你一起来了吗
Is mom with you?
没有
No!
发生什么事了
What's going on?
-我不想让妈妈看到  -看到什么
- I didn't want mom to see. - See what?
他怎么了
What happened to him?
他做了治安维持者的靶子
Vigilante decided to use him as target practice.
你是对的
You're right--
那人是个疯子
the guy's a psycho.
你为什么不去医院
Why didn't you go to the hospital?
在这座城市
In this city,
中箭会像中枪一样引来警方的注意
an arrow's the same as a bullet if you want the cops involved.
虽然妈妈挺喜欢罗伊的
And mom actually likes Roy,
但要是她发现他和兜帽男纠缠不清
but something tells me she'd revoke his tree trimming invitation
她一定不会让他装饰圣诞树了
if she found out he was messing around with the hood.
罗伊
Roy.
会很疼的
This is going to hurt.
我的愤怒能冲淡疼痛
My anger's dulling the pain.
这个能冲得更淡
This will dull it better.
然后用力按住  就这样
Going to put pressure on it. Right there.
狄格尔  我需要你来一趟奎恩宅邸
Diggle, I need you to come to the Queen mansion.
罗伊被射中了
Roy's been shot.
中的是箭
With an arrow.
说来话长
It's a long story.
先把急救箱拿来西娅的房间
Look, just bring the first aid kit to Thea's room.
谢谢
Thank you.
罗伊  我的司机狄格尔先生
Roy, my driver, Mr. Diggle,
在部队的时候受过医疗训练
he has medical training from his time in the army.
-他会帮你包扎  -谢谢
- He's going to patch you up. - Thank you.
不过是尽我所能
It's the least I can do.
我不知道你们三个想干什么
Look, I don't know what the three of you are up to,
但也许治安维持者只是想保证你们的安全
but maybe the vigilante was just trying to keep you safe.
所以他才射了罗伊吗
By shooting Roy?
我只是猜测
I... i'm just saying.
也许你们应该放手
Maybe you should let this go.
所以  你会放手吗
So... are you going to let this go?
不
No.
但现在起一切听我的
But now we're going to do things my way.
妈妈
Mom!
有人吗
Hello!
你好  我的爱人
Hello, my love.
莎朵
Shado?
你不可能是真的
You can't be here.
我必须来见你
I had to see you.
-我得警告你  -警告我
- Had to warn you. - Warn me?
你无法抵抗接下来要发生的事
You can't fight what's coming.
放下你的弓
Put down your bow.
脱下我父亲的兜帽
Take off my father's hood.
我戴兜帽是为了纪念你父亲
I wear that hood to honor your father.
也为了纪念你
And to honor you.
如果你想纪念我
If you want to honor me,
停止争斗  好好生活
stop fighting...and live.
不然所有你爱的人都会死
Or everyone you love will die.
奥利
Ollie?
你刚刚在和谁讲话
Who were you talking to?
放下武器
Put off your weapons.
滚过去
Get over there!
奇迹
Mirakuru.
把他们带走
Take them.
安东尼
Anthony...
你已经得偿所愿了
you got what you wanted.
你可以放了他们
You can let them go.
要是你真正在乎过我
If you ever cared about me.
我确实在乎你  莎拉
But I do care about you, Sara.
所以我不会选择杀你
Which is why I won't choose to kill you.
但是他可能会
But he might.
你什么意思
What are you talking about?
是时候做出选择了  奥利弗
Time to choose, Oliver.
选出谁生  谁死
Who lives, and who dies.
不过你得选快点  因为30秒后
But pick quickly, because in 30 seconds,
我会把她们都杀了
I will shoot them both.
孵化已经开始了
The incubation process has begun.
48小时后就可以散播血清
Serum will be ready for distribution in 48 hours.
只要两天
Two days.
我们就能创造上百个像你一样的人
And we will be able to create a hundred more like you.
这座城市的掌权人
And the people who run this city
终于能见识到真正的力量了
will see what real power looks like.
我就知道治安维持者有同伙
I knew the vigilante had partners.
他现在比较喜欢绿箭侠这个称呼
He likes to be called the Arrow now.
你们三个和一些真正的人渣较量过
You three have messed with some really nasty people.
娃娃制造者  迷魂伯爵
The Doll Maker, Count Vertigo,
幕后者还有女杀手
Dodger, the Huntress.
我们没有记录在案
We weren't keeping score.
我记着呢
I was.
巴里
Barry.
你给我用的老鼠药  有没有副作用
The rat poison that you gave me... are there any side effects?
有  可能出现幻觉
Um, yeah, I think hallucinations, maybe.
以及大量出汗
And excessive sweating.
你有没有出很多汗
Are you sweating excessively?
你产生幻觉了吗
You're hallucinating?
你看到什么了
What are you seeing?
一个叫莎朵的女孩  和我一起在岛上待过
A girl named Shado that was with me on the island.
莎朵
Shado.
莎拉
Sara.
你和多少女人一起被困岛上
How many women were you marooned with?
你确定那个岛不是虚构吗
Are you sure this wasn't fantasy island?
你果然是在森林或者丛林里接受的训练
You did train in a jungle or forest environment,
所以才选了绿色
hence the green.
让我抽点血  看看怎么样了
Hey, let me draw some blood, see what's up.
我能问你个事吗
Hey, can I ask you something?
为什么不戴面具
Why no mask?
我不是想教你该怎么去维持治安
Not to tell you how to do your vigilante...ing,
只是涂油彩
but the grease paint thing?
不是个隐藏身份的好办法
It's a poor identity concealer.
那你去帮我找个既能完美适合我的脸型
So find me a mask that conforms perfectly to my face
在我奔跑的同时又完全不妨碍到瞄准力的面具
and doesn't affect my ability to aim while I'm on the run.
你可以试试可压缩的超细纤维
You should look into a compressible micro fabric.
-会非常好用的  -发现塞勒斯·戈尔德
- It could be great. - Found Cyrus Gold.
塞勒斯·戈尔德是谁
Who's Gyrus Gold?
那天晚上差点把你弄死的那个人体武器
The human weapon that left you nearly dead the other night.
那家伙从你脖子上取下了他的指纹
The kid did manage to pull his print off your neck.
我用人脸识别软件
I've had facial recognition software
扫描全城的闭路式摄像机
scanning closed circuit cameras all over town.
他现在在德尔加多大街和第二十五大道处
He's at the corner of Delgado and 25th right now,
但是马上要跟丢了
but we're just about to lose him.
那个十字路口上还有什么
What else is at that intersection?
停车场  超市  汽车旅馆
A parking lot, a market, a motel.
很可能就是他的藏身之所
Could be where he's holed up.
-我来搞定  -奥利弗
- I got this. - Oliver...
这件事我来处理吧
Why don't let me handle this one?
只是侦察而已
It's just recon.
好吧
Fine.
我做你的后援
But I'm going as your back-up.
别担心
Don't worry.
我会查出奥利弗到底怎么回事的
I'll figure out what's wrong with Oliver.
你尽早吧
You'd be the first.
需要议员陪你一起去做圣诞节采购吗
神秘的爱慕者吗
Secret admirer?
不是的  是我爸送来的
No, actually, they're from my father.
什么风把你吹来了
What brings you by?
我们需要你的帮助  辛迪的朋友被杀了
We need your help. Cindy's friend was murdered,
但是警方不肯介入调查
but the police aren't going to investigate.
说是吸毒过量致死  就这样
They said that he ODed, end of story.
看看这个
Check this out.
他献血赚外快
He earned extra money donating blood.
贫民区救灾献血活动
我们在马克斯房间里找到的
We found it in Max's apartment.
如果他吸毒  他们不会要他的血  对吧
They wouldn't have accepted his blood if he was using, right?
马克斯和献血车同天消失的
Max went missing the same day as the blood drive.
如果他真的去那献血了
If he did donate blood there,
至少他们会知道点马克斯的情况吧
maybe they at least know something that happened to him.
我去打听一下
I'll ask around.
谢谢你  劳蕾尔
Thank you, Laurel.
帕特丽夏饭店
如果无聊  储备箱里有本填字游戏的书
If you get bored, I keep a book of crossword puzzles in the glove box.
这话一点都不好笑
That's not funny.
你看到什么了
Ok, what do you see?
房间很干净
It's clean.
非常干净
Really clean.
"所罗门·格兰迪  周一出生..."
"Solomon Grundy, born on a Monday..."
周二洗礼
Christened on Tuesday.
我知道那首诗  象征着生命的七个阶段
I know the poem. It symbolizes the seven stages of life--
从出生到死亡
From birth to death.
这家伙现在处于哪个阶段
What stage is this guy in?
快走快走  快  快
Go, go, go, go, go!
他轻而易举地就能把我拎起来
He picked me up like I was nothing.
-费利西蒂  请求支援  -马上来
- Felicity, call for back-up.  - On it.
是莎拉的事吗
This about Sara?
你有她的消息吗
You heard from her?
没有
No.
抱歉  这是...
I'm sorry, this is...
是别的事
This is something else.
塞勒斯·戈尔德
Cyrus Gold.
上周他到奎恩联合企业的
He robbed the Applied Sciences division
应用科学部门偷了东西
of Queen Consolidated last week.
警探
Detective...
他是个危险分子
He's extremely dangerous.
从中心城市派来的现场调查员
The CSI kid from central city,
他说这人就像某种怪物
he said this guy was like some kind of monster.
确实是
He is.
是什么东西  用了类固醇吗
Well, what is it, steroids?
更糟糕  是...
Worse. It's--
那个是...
It's...
好吧  就算我相信你  你为什么来找我
Well, assuming I believe you, why come to me?
我妥协了
I've been compromised.
什么意思
What does that mean?
意思是我现在是个累赘
It means I'd be a liability.
这事你必须相信我  警探
You have to take my word on this, detective.
尽可能召集多的人手
Gather as many men as you can,
能杀死塞勒斯·戈尔德的时候一定不要犹豫
and do not hesitate to kill Cyrus Gold.
因为如果他有机会
Because if given the opportunity,
他也会毫不犹豫地杀了你
he'll do the same to you.
你不需要这么做
You don't have to do this!
你拿到了你想要的东西
You got what you came for!
拿上东西走吧
Just take it and go!
还剩十秒
10 seconds.
你这变态的神经病
You freaking psychopath!
历史自有决断
History will make that judgment.
还剩五秒
Five seconds.
时间到
Time's up.
不  不
No, no!
我想你已经做出了选择
I guess you made your choice.
不
No!
你来这里干什么
What are you doing here?
我是来找西娅的
I came by to see Thea.
进来吧
Go on in.
她在楼上她的房间里
She's upstairs in her room.
我开车过来的时候注意到
I noticed on the drive up that your house
你们家没有布置圣诞装饰
wasn't festooned with Christmas decorations.
我们今年不是
Well, we didn't feel very much like
很想布置
festooning this year.
我知道你的意思
I know what you mean.
我记得去年圣诞节
I remember last Christmas,
汤米和我来参加你们的聚会
Tommy and I came here for your party.
那是我很长时间以来过的最好的节日
It was one of the best holidays I'd had in a really long time.
我该去找西娅了
Anyway, I should probably go talk to Thea.
我调查了献血活动
I checked into the blood drive,
是完全合法的
and it's all legitimate.
实际上  塞巴斯蒂安的工作
In fact, what Sebastian's done
已经帮忙拯救了许多生命
has helped save a lot of lives.
如果献血活动是合法有益的
So if the blood drive is on the up and up,
那我们该怎么找到杀马克斯的凶手
then how are we supposed to find Max's killer?
还有一件事
There's one other thing.
所有参加活动的献血者
All of the blood donors at the drive
都参加了兰福德研究所的
were subjected to a psych evaluation
精神评估
by the Langford Institute.
那是合法的吗
Is that, like, legal?
这并不是完全不合常理
It's not entirely out of the norm.
研究所的人
And while someone at the
应该知道马克斯有没有被下毒
institute might know if Max was on drugs,
贫民区救灾献血活动
没有搜查令是没法查出来的
There's no way of finding out without a warrant.
我们又没法拿到搜查令
Which we're certainly not going to get.
很抱歉我只能帮到这里了
I'm sorry I couldn't be more help.
你在干什么
What are you doing?
只是随便弄点东西
Uh, just messing around with something.
你不是应该在查奥利弗
Shouldn't you be trying to figure out
产生幻觉的原因吗
what's causing Oliver's hallucinations?
样本还在扫描  应该快好了
Sample's still being scanned. Shouldn't be too much longer.
很好
Good.
你真的很担心他  对吧
You're really worried about him, huh?
他总是冒很大的险
He takes crazy chances.
即使是在他不幻想
Even when he's not hallucinating
岛上那些漂亮姑娘的时候
about beautiful island girls.
那天晚上  我问你是不是喜欢奥利弗
The other night, I asked you if you liked Oliver.
我跟你说了  我不喜欢
I told you. I don't.
我记得
I remember.
但如果你喜欢...
But if you did...
我能看出原因
I could see why.
我是说  奥利弗·奎因
I mean, Oliver Queen.
白天他是个百万富翁
He is a billionaire by day
晚上他拯救城市
and saves the city by night.
听起来你想跟他约会啊
Sounds like you want to date him.
我是刚刚开始喜欢一个
I just have a little experience with liking someone
用不同于他人的眼光看我的人
who doesn't see you the same way.
今晚粒子加速器的启动进入倒计时
Protests continue into the final countdown
对尖端科技研究实验室颇具争议的
for tonight's ignition of S.T.A.R.
抗议活动还在继续
Lab's controversial particle accelerator.
尖端科技研究实验室的创始人哈里森·威尔斯
S.T.A.R. Lab's founder Harrison Wells promises a new era
硬粒子加速器开启倒计时
声称科技进步的新纪元即将到来
of scientific advancement is at hand.
我想我来不及回去看他们开启加速器了
I guess I won't be back in time to see them turn it on.
我知道  是听起来很疯狂
I know, it sounds crazy.
人体武器
Human weapons?
他的名字叫塞勒斯·戈尔德
Look, his name is Cyrus Gold.
他就是上周闯入奎恩联合企业的人
He's the one that broke into Queen Consolidated last week.
就是他抢了血库
He's the one that robbed the blood bank.
也是他杀了那些人
And he killed all those people.
等等
Wait, hold on a second.
你怎么知道这些的
Where are you getting all this intel?
伙计  你是怎么了
Oh, man, what's a matter with you?
你就是因为跟治安维持者联系而降职的
Talking to Wigilante's what got you demoted in the first place.
听着  我们带一支小队去
Look, we take a small squad.
特警队的麦卡西和埃文斯  还有琼斯
Mccarthy and Evans from SWAT, Jones.
我们可以抓住这个家伙的
We can bring this guy down.
我答应过珍妮带她去圣诞采购
I promised Jeannie I'd take her Christmas shopping.
卢卡斯
Lucas.
拜托
Please.
好吧
Fine.
但你得给珍妮打电话告诉她
But you get to call Jeanie and tell her
我没法带她去购物了
I'm not taking her shopping.
长官
Hey, Sir.
我不想越级
I don't mean to overstep,
但你能多带一个人吗
but could you guys use an extra man?
去穿件防弹衣  戴利警官
Grab a vest, Officer Daily.
警察盯上戈尔德了
The police are onto Gold.
他们在找他
They're looking for him.
我确信已经混进了队伍
I made sure I'm in the loop.
现在绝对不能让警察影响到我们
We are too close to let the police interfere.
塞拉斯兄弟
Brother Cyrus.
警察很想见你
The police are eager to meet you.
介绍一下你自己
Introduce yourself.
圣诞节有什么计划吗
So, any plans for Christmas?
点亮我的烛台[犹太节日所用]
Lighting my menorah.
感觉怎么样
Hi. How are you feeling?
还行
Fine. Just...
家里人多拥挤
It's a little bit crowded at my house,
我就想过来  一个人静静
and I wanted to come down here to get a little privacy.
没问题
Yeah.
走吧  巴里
Come on, Barry.
去大胃王汉堡店看倒计时也行
We can watch the countdown at big belly burger.
你的血液分析快完成了
Your blood analysis is almost done.
谢谢
Thank you.
怎么了  小子
What's the matter, kid?
一脸看到鬼的样子
You look like you've seen a ghost.
你确定他在里面吗
Are you sure he's in there?
是的  长官
Yes, sir.
有人看到塞勒斯·戈尔德进去
Sector car spotted Cyrus Gold entering.
一直没有出来
He hasn't left.
手枪保险都打开
Safeties off.
他在那边  包围过去
Over there. Surround him.
这地方不错啊
This is a nice place.
比荒岛上的破碎机舱
It's a bit more comfortable
稍微舒服点
than the fuselage on the island.
你不是真的
You're not real.
你也不是
Neither are you.
你对别人说  掀起这场变革
You told everyone when you started this crusade
是为了
that it was about
弥补你父亲犯下的罪恶
making up for your father's sins.
真是谎话连篇
That was a lie.
你是为自己赎罪
This charade is to atone for your sins.
你已经死了
You're dead.
你不是什么英雄
You are not a hero.
也不配当朋友兄弟  你屁都不是
Or a friend. Or a brother. You are nothing.
不要背对着我[背叛我]
Do not turn your back on me,
第二次了
not again.
你已经去世了
You're gone.
不管我现在在哪...
Wherever I am...
你应该加入我
It's time you joined me.
莎翁说过懦夫一生千次死
They say a coward dies a thousand deaths.
可是你死一千次也不够
But even that wouldn't be enough for you.
我试过救你
I tried to save you!
还有她
And her.
可你没做到
But you couldn't.
正如你也救不了这座城市
Just like you couldn't save this city.
那座岛根本没让你变强
The island didn't make you strong, kid.
反而暴露出你的软弱
It revealed you to be weak.
谢谢你当我的购物指导
Thank you for being my shopping guide.
你还好吗
Are you ok?
我没事  那个
Uh, yeah, it's just, um,
我可以问你个问题吗
can I ask you a question?
关于你发起的献血活动
It's about the blood drive you sponsored.
当然  那是好事一桩
Of course. It's a wonderful cause.
尤其是对于那些资金不足的医院来说
Especially with the underfunded hospitals we're dealing with.
怎么了
What about it?
喂
Hello?
什么
What?!
好的  我马上过来
Ok, I'll be right over.
怎么了
What happened?
我爸爸
My father.
他受重伤住院了  抱歉
He's in the ICU. I'm so sorry.
非常抱歉  我得先走了
I'm so sorry, I have to go.
不好意思
I'm sorry.
发生什么事了
What happened in here?
有人闯进来过吗
Did someone break in?
没有
No.
你的血液分析结果出来了  好消息
Your blood analysis is done. Good news.
查到里面有什么了吗
So you know what's in my system?
问题就在这里  你的血液很干净
That's the thing-- your blood's clean.
没有任何问题
There's nothing wrong with you.
那我为什么会产生幻觉
Then why am I hallucinating?!
我不知道
I don't know.
不管问题出在哪
But whatever your problem is,
肯定不是生理原因  而是心理问题
it's not pharmacological. It's psychological.
-是你的臆想  -是我的臆想
- It's in your head. - It's in my head.
老天
Oh, my god.
奥利弗
Oliver.
爸
Dad!
宝贝
Honey.
我的脚趾还能动  应该是个好迹象
Well, I can wiggle my toes, it must be a good sign.
我没事  亲爱的
I'm all right, honey, I'm fine.
卢卡斯怎么样  他还好吗
How's Lucas, is he all right?
对不起
I--I'm sorry.
你这是什么意思
What do you mean?
我得打电话告诉他妻子珍妮
I got to call Jeannie. I got to call his wife.
爸  你待着别动  我去打
No, dad, I'll do it. You just...stay here.
你好好休息
Get some rest.
你来这里干什么
What are you doing here?
来看看你爸爸有没有事
Wanted to make sure your father was ok.
他没事
He is.
顺便也看看你还好吗
I wanted to make sure you were, too.
你怎么样  警探
How are you, detective?
没死
I'm alive.
我的同伴就没这么幸运了
Unlike most everyone else in my unit.
关于您搭档的事我很遗憾
I'm sorry about your partner.
是我带他进去的
I took him in there.
是因为我
Because of me.
我不想让你失望
I hate to disappoint you,
但你没必要对这城市的每桩命案负责
but not every death in this city is on you.
从戈尔德身上拿到的
I got this off Gold.
希望能帮到你
Hopefully you can do something with it.
开始我还不相信  但这个人
I didn't believe it at first, but this guy,
根本不像是人类
I mean, it's like he's not human.
他是人类
He's human.
那就杀了他
Well, then you can kill him.
为希尔顿  也为我
For Hilton. And me.
我觉得够锋利了
I think those are sharp enough.
很显然我不这么认为
Apparently I'm not.
狄格尔  你觉得我是神经错乱了吗
Diggle, do you think I'm losing my mind?
没比我们差多少
No more than the rest of us.
我看到
I saw...
斯莱德·威尔逊
Slade Wilson.
斯莱德是我在小岛上的朋友
Slade was my friend on the island,
而且
and...
他和莎朵一样  因我而死
like Shado, he is dead because of me.
兰斯先生说
Mr. Lance just told me
我没必要对这城市的每桩命案负责
that not every death in this city is my fault.
确实
Fine.
但确实有很多是我的责任
There are plenty that are.
当我从阿富汗回来时  我
When I got home from Afghanistan, I...
也看到了个鬼魂
saw a ghost, too.
幸存者的内疚
Survivor's guilt.
为什么我们独活
Why us, not them.
我知道为什么
I know why.
那这"为什么"就不是你的问题
Then the "Why's" not your problem.
你是怎么赶走鬼魂的
How'd you make your ghost go away?
我明白了他们想告诉我的意思
I figured out what they were trying to tell me.
是什么
Which was?
那是说给我听的  奥利弗
That's for me to hear, Oliver.
你得搞清你的那鬼魂想告诉你什么
You have to figure out what yours is trying to tell you.
伙计们  有新发现
Guys, we got something here.
我扫描了兰斯给你的钥匙
I scanned the key Lance gave you,
通过序列号查到了它的生产商
and traced its serial code back to the manufacturer.
这把钥匙和贫民区新月环路某处
This particular key fits a locked gate
一个上锁的门相匹配
somewhere on Crescent Circle in the glades.
你要去哪里
Where are you going?
你这身体状况不能随便跑出去
You can't go out there in your condition.
我必须阻止他们
I have to stop this.
奥利弗  戈尔德没直接把你打死
Oliver, Gold left you half dead,
比起希尔顿警探的遭遇可真是手下留情了
which is 50 percent better than how he left detective hilton.
费利西蒂
Felicity...
我别无选择
I don't have a choice.
我会回来的
I'll come back.
你发誓
Promise me.
兰福德研究所
马克斯
Max.
米拉库鲁
万事俱备
It's ready.
这就是你杀马克斯·斯坦顿的地方吗
Is this where you killed max stanton, hmm?
你要干嘛  敢用它扎我  我就杀了你
What are you doing? If you stick that in me, I'll kill you.
不  罗伊兄弟
No, Brother Roy.
你会为我杀人
You'll kill for me.
勒斯兄弟说他已经把你杀了
Brother Cyrus told me he killed you.
也许他没你想得那么强大
Guess he's not as strong as you'd hoped.
你从哪里得到的米拉库鲁  谁给你的配方
Where'd you get the Mirakiru? Who gave you the formula?!
那是一件可以用来拯救这座城市的礼物
It was a gift. A gift I would use to save this city from itself.
另一件失败品
Another failure.
站起来  奥利弗
Get up, Oliver.
汤米
Tommy?
你不能死在这里
You're not going to die down here.
汤米  对不起
Tommy, I'm sorry.
你是因我而死
I let you die.
我不是因你而死  奥利
You didn't let me die, Ollie.
你为了救我而战
You fought to save me.
因为你就是这样的人
Because that's what you do.
一如既往
What you have always done.
为生存而战
You fight to survive.
我知道我曾叫你杀人犯
I know I called you a murderer,
但你不是
but you are not.
你是个英雄
You are a hero.
你战胜了那座小岛
You beat the island.
你战胜了我父亲
You beat my father.
战斗下去  奥利弗
So fight, Oliver.
站起来
Get up,
以牙还牙
and fight back.
杀了他
Kill him.
我不会再眼睁睁看着别人死去
Hey. I am not leaving anyone else to die!
你很坚强  孩子
You're strong, kid.
加油  加油
Come on! Come on!
加油  罗伊
Come on, Roy!
战胜它  加油  战胜它
Fight. Come on, fight!
罗伊
Roy?!
Hey, Roy!
你去哪了  我到处找你
Where have you been? I've been looking all over for you!
我
I was...
我去追踪一条线索
I was running down another lead.
似乎不太成功
It didn't pan out.
我还以为你又去找治安维持者了
I thought you were chasing after the vigilante again.
我吓坏了  还以为你出什么事了
I got so scared. I thought something happened to you.
听我说  别担心
Hey, hey, don't worry.
我活得好好的
I'm alive.
我要为星城的人民大众服务
I want to serve the people of Starling,
布拉德宣布参选市长
而不是为那些自以为拥有这城市的人
not the men and women who think they own it.
携起手来  重建我们的城市
Together, we can help rebuild our city
不再有阶级  不再有压迫
into a place where there are no elites and no oppressed.
人人都是兄弟姐妹
Where we are all brothers and sisters.
看来你的竞选开始了
So your campaign begins.
星城需要领袖
The city needs a leader.
让冒牌兜帽男刺杀市长
And putting the copycat hoods up to assassinating the Mayor
只是第一步
was just the first step.
治安维持者
The vigilante...
他摧毁了离心机
He destroyed the centrifuge
也破坏了血清
and the serum along with it.
我会再给你提供一份我的血样
I will arrange for you to receive another sample of my blood,
然后你就可以再次大批量制血清
and then you can begin to mass produce the serum again.
如果我不允许你与治安维持者对峙
When I ask you not to confront the vigilante,
你要听令
you will listen.
记住  你的面具别人也可以戴
Remember, your mask can be worn by another.
你知道兜帽男是谁  对吧
You know who he is under that hood, don't you?
我再清楚不过了
I know exactly who he is.
他是我的朋友
He's my friend.
怪不得你不希望他死
That's why you don't want him dead.
死亡是一种解脱
Death would be a release from this life,
他还没有接受审判
and his sentence is yet to be carried out.
我要摧毁他所在乎的一切
I am going to tear everything he cares about away from him.
制裁所有追随他的人
Destroy those who choose to follow him.
蹂躏他至爱之人
Corrupt those he loves.
待他失去了
Once he has lost everyone
所有至亲至爱
and everything he values...
我再用箭刺穿他的头颅
I will drive an arrow through his eye.
莎朵
Shado...
Shado!
不
No!
为什么
Why?
我...
I...
艾沃开枪打死了她
Ivo just shot her.
不知道为什么
He didn't say why.
不管是谁做的
Whoever did this to her...
我要他血债血偿
has got to suffer.
还有幻觉吗
Still have a ghost problem?
没有了
No.
我明白意思了
I got the message.
不过...
But we...
还有其他问题
We have other problems.
要没问题就奇怪了
Wouldn't be us if we didn't.
罗伊被注射了血清
Roy was injected with the serum.
天啊  他怎么样了
Oh, my god, is he ok?
还活着
He's alive.
不过我们得看着他
But we are going to have to keep an eye on him.
塞勒斯·戈尔德呢
And Cyrus Gold?
死于周六  周日安葬
Died on Saturday, buried on Sunday.
但他还有个同伙
But he was working with someone.
我看见他戴了一副面具
I saw him, he wore a mask
上边画着  骷髅
with the image of a...of a skull.
他想大批量生产血清  然后建立军队
He's trying to mass produce the serum to build an army.
为什么
For what?
你是一名军人
You're a soldier.
军队的首要天职是什么
What's the primary purpose of an army?
战争
War.
巴里呢
Where's Barry?
他回中心城市了
He went back to Central City.
想及时赶回去
Wanted to get home in time
看他们打开粒子加速器
to see them turn on the particle accelerator.
我接个电话
I should take this.
到了吗
Did you make it?
我及时赶回了中心城市
I made it back to Central City in time,
不过我很怀念尖端科研实验室与世隔绝的生活
But I missed the cut off in line at S.T.A.R. Labs.
跟往常一样  我迟到了
I was late, as usual.
但是我可不想再迟到了
But in spirit of not being late again,
你什么时候觉得
uh, if you ever decide that
奥利弗·奎恩不适合你
Oliver Queen isn't the guy for you;
或者觉得
if you decide that
想跟不一样的人
you want to go on a date with
约会
someone else, um...
我想告诉你  那个人一定会准时的
You should know that that guy, he'll be on time.
很好
Good to know.
我给奥利弗留了个东西
Oh, hey, and I left something for Oliver.
希望他会喜欢
I hope he likes it.
再见  巴里
Bye, Barry.
再见  费利西蒂
Bye, Felicity.
我是琳达·帕克
I'm Linda Park
尖端科研实验室外现场直播
and we're live outside S.T.A.R. Labs
天气状况十分恶劣  并且有恶化倾向
Despite the inclement weather, which is only going to get worse.
瓢泼大雨赶走了几乎所有抗议者
The torrential downpour has driven away almost all the protesters
尖端科研实验室总裁哈里森·威尔斯向我们保证
though S.T.A.R. Labs CEO Harrison Wells has assured us
今晚的风暴
that the storm tonight will
绝不会影响到粒子加速器
in no way affect the particle accelerator,
目前其运转一切正常
which is up and running smoothly.
医生被指控谋杀妻子
诺拉·艾伦死亡
诺拉·艾伦被其丈夫谋杀
我们现在被告知紧急疏散
Wait, we are now being told to evacuate the facility.
风暴可能使主冷却系统
the storm may have caused a malfunction
发生了故障
to the primary cooling system.
工作人员正在试图关掉粒子加速器
Officials are now trying to shut down the particle accelerator,
粒子加速器已打开
但是目前仍然无法重新控制系统
but so far have been unable to regain control of the system.
连绿箭侠也有圣诞礼物
Even the Arrow deserves a Christmas present.
戴上
Here.
怎么样
How do I look?
像英雄
Like a hero.